liveperson.net 2008-03-17

# Live chat, email management, click to talk software by LivePerson

| 

At LivePerson, we have created this privacy policy because we are concerned about protecting the privacy of the users of our live online customer service. LivePerson edeavors to be in compliance with data privacy laws and regulations, including the EU Directive 95-46. As such we have obtained "safe harbor" status from the US Department of Commerce which entails adopting the data quality principles set forth in the EU data privacy directive. The success of our service depends on our ability to maintain the trust of these users. Please read on for more information about our privacy policy. 

## What does LivePerson do?

LivePerson is a leading provider of technology that facilitates real-time sales and customer service for companies doing business on the Internet. We are an Application Service Provider, or ASP, and we offer our proprietary real-time interaction technology as an outsourced service to our customers. As an ASP, we collect information on behalf of our customers. We also collect information on our own website. Our methods for collection and use of information depend on whether the user logs directly onto our website (a "LivePerson User") or accesses our service on one of our customer's sites (an "ASP User").

## LivePerson Users

When the online customer service chat first begins, LivePerson Users are asked to enter their names in whatever format or detail they prefer. During the chat, LivePerson Users enter into a live question and answer session with an operator. We maintain dialogue transcripts of these chats. After the chat, we ask LivePerson Users to fill out an exit survey in order to obtain valuable feedback about our service. Filling out the exit survey is completely voluntary. The surveys may ask for contact information (e.g., email address) and for demographic information (e.g., zip code, age or income level). 

LivePerson Users in need of technical support are required to complete a form for purposes of defining and clarifying their technical support requests. When submitting a technical support request, LivePerson Users are asked to provide the following identifiable information: email address, URL of their site and a description of the issue. Emails sent to support are kept only for problem solving purposes and this information is not shared with or disclosed to any outside third parties.

We log browser information (e.g., Internet Protocol addresses and browser types) to help diagnose problems with our server, gather broad demographic information and administer our site.

We also collect data through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our site.

We do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 18 years of age. The exit surveys ask LivePerson Users to enter their age so that we may refuse to accept any information that has been submitted by anyone under 18.

We access the information we collect for certain purposes (for example, to aggregate the information, to monitor the use of the service during certain chats and for other lawful purposes). A LivePerson User's information, including personally identifiable information, will not be shared with anyone. We do not sell, trade or rent the personal information that LivePerson Users provide.

## ASP Users

When the online customer service chat first begins, ASP Users may be asked to enter their names or other personal information to facilitate service. By providing such personal information, ASP User consents to LivePerson collecting and processing such personal information on behalf of itself or its customers. Also, during the chat, ASP Users enter into a live question and answer session with an operator. We maintain dialogue transcripts of these chats. After the chat, our customers may ask ASP Users to fill out an exit survey in order to obtain valuable feedback. Filling out the exit survey is completely voluntary. The surveys may ask for contact information (e.g., email address) and for demographic information (e.g., zip code, age or income level). The surveys vary by customer so that our customers may obtain feedback specific to their website and business, as well as feedback regarding our service.

We log browser information (e.g., Internet Protocol addresses and browser types) to help diagnose problems with our server, gather broad demographic information and administer our site. By choosing to engage in a chat and use the services, ASP User consents to such logging and processing of IP address.

We do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 18 years of age. The exit surveys ask ASP Users to enter their age so that our clients may refuse to accept any information that has been submitted by anyone under 18.

We access the information we collect for certain purposes including, but not limited to, the following: to provide maintenance, support or professional services to our customers, to aggregate the information, to monitor the use of the service during certain chats and for other lawful purposes.

An ASP User's information contained in the dialogue transcripts and the exit surveys may be shared with our customer on whose website the ASP User accessed our service (the "ASP Customer"). Furthermore, such information may be shared with others on an aggregate basis. Personally identifiable information or business information related to an ASP Customer or ASP User (supplied voluntarily during the chat or in the exit survey) will not be shared with parties other than the ASP Customer, except as required by law. We actively encourage the ASP Customers to post a privacy policy on their site and to ensure that their use of the information will comply with their privacy policy.

We do not sell, trade or rent the personally identifiable information that ASP Users provide.

## Information Relevant to Both LivePerson Users and ASP Users

Our site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We offer secure sessions for chats at our clients' option so that data passed between users and operators cannot be decrypted. To achieve this level of security, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption that encodes information as it is being sent over the Internet between the user and the operator. All chats and user data are maintained and archived on secure servers. Access to stored data is password protected and passwords are account specific. Therefore, no customer can view data for another customer. We also use appropriate firewall technology within our facility to prevent unauthorized access. For another level of protection, all data is backed up daily, and archives are stored off-site in a secure location.

Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that website and are used for record-keeping purposes at many websites. Use of cookies makes Web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving passwords, lists of potential purchases, personal preferences regarding the use of the particular website and to make sure the user does not see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard. Our site uses cookies to enhance the user's experience by allowing us to recognize a user's return visit to our own service. 

Browsers are usually set to accept cookies. However, if users would prefer not to receive cookies, they may alter the configuration of their browser to refuse cookies. If they choose to have their browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our site will not function as effectively when viewed by the users.

LivePerson gives users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include opting not to engage in chat sessions and opting not to provide identifiable information during chat sessions. 

We are committed to protecting the privacy of the users of our service. We use the information we collect to provide a better experience for future use of our service and to provide our customers with valuable feedback on their websites and businesses.

If any of the personal information that you provided to us changes or is incorrect, please [email us](mailto:records@liveperson.com) with your new, correct information.

In the event that someone buys or acquires us or substantially all of our assets, our information about you and your use of our services will likely be one of the acquired assets.

## Tell us what you think

LivePerson welcomes your feedback on our privacy policy. Send your comments to [privacy@liveperson.com](mailto:privacy@liveperson.com).

We recommend that you review this policy periodically, as we may update it from time to time.

|
